[Music]
hello friends
welcome back to our channel
i am your tosca instructor and my name
is kumaresh
i have total 14 years of it experience
in software development and test
automation thank you for connecting with
us
hope you are doing well
let's start our today's session
through this video i will explain the
overview of tosca test case
also i will guide to develop the test
cases with the help of modules which are
created during the last tutorial
test case is a set of instructions to
ensure the quality of the software
product
in other word it is a combination of
steps to walk through the application
with verification
the test cases are written based on the
software requirements
it can be designed for manual or
automated testing
[Music]
here we are going to discuss about test
cases that are automated by tosca
the tosca test cases are created by
using the both standard and user-defined
modules with required test data
two types of test cases are available in
tosca
technical test cases
and business test cases
[Music]
the technical test case keeps all the
technical information to steer the
controls during execution
it can be created by right clicking on
any folder which are available in test
case section and selecting the blue
colored circular arrow icon
the shortcut key for new test case
creation are control plus n and control
plus t
it is a collection of test steps which
are created by the drag and dropping of
modules
test steps has different action modes
such as
the input action mode is used while
entering data perform click operations
the insert action mode is used for
insert purpose
the verify action mode is required to
select this option during verification
in the value field we need to provide
the condition
the buffer action mode is used to set
the value to buffer
the walton action mode is used for
synchronization purposes to wait until
the condition is satisfied
the select action mode is used while
hierarchy levels are available and need
to work on child items
the constraint action mode is used for
checking for a particular value mostly
used in the tables column
[Music]
the test cases has three status
planning
in work and
completed
[Music]
the business test cases are the logical
groups of technical test cases
each of the business test case
represents the functionality coverage
which is designed based on the
requirements
the business test cases are not
executable
only we can monitor the testing coverage
through this
all right
let's start the test case development
process in tosca
we will automate a simple scenario on
google search to understand the test
automation development
the scenario involved with steps such as
launch google in chrome browser
search text tricentes tosca in google
click on first search result to open
official portal
and verify that trycentus official page
has appeared
the required custom modules are already
created with the reference of last video
on tosca modules
all right
let's start the test case creation
process
three user defined modules are already
created for google search screen search
results screen and the trisentis tosca
official portal
we have added only the required controls
during the module creation
[Music]
now we will move to the project
hierarchy and dock the component test
cases as tabs
[Music]
as we are working with the shared
repository
first we need to check out the test
cases section
after that we need to create the folder
structure
the proper folder structure creation is
an optional task but it's in best
practice
we can logically segregate the test
cases using folder
now we will create new test case by
right clicking on the new folder and
provide a logical name
[Music]
the technical test case is created now
it's an empty test case which means no
test steps are available
our next task is to add test step by
referring the modules based on the
activity
[Music]
as our first step is launching the
application so we need to use the
standard modules which is available
under t-box automation tools process
automation
we need to drag and drop this modules to
the test case
[Music]
this module helped to launch any
application
but tosca provides a specific modules to
launch any web browser with url
so we delete this one and use the
standard module open url to launch web
application
the standard module open url is
available under module folders t-box
engines html
we need to drag and drop this module to
the test case
[Music]
we will now enter the url as
www.google.com and select the action
mode as input
[Music]
it's advisable to rename the test step
logically as per the activity to be
performed
the first test step is ready now
as per this step the google search will
appear
now we will look for the second step
here we need to search the text try
sentence tosca in google
we will now add our first custom module
the custom module google search screen
will be used to create test step to
perform google search
[Music]
rename the test step accordingly
here we will use the weight on as action
mode for the control google icon to
handle synchronization
we will check the exist property as true
for white on
set the string value as trisentis tosca
for the field queue search text with
action mode input
this step will enter the search text in
google search field
now click operation has to be added as
value for the control google search
button and the action mode should be
input
[Music]
this step will perform the click
operation
the second test step is completed
it will enter the search text into
google and click on the search button
the next step is to click on the first
result option to open the trisentis
official portal
sometime google search is not first
enough due to the network condition
so it's a good practice to add a pause
here
for this purpose we will add the
standard module wait to perform the
pause
[Music]
we will configure the wait time as 5
seconds by entering value as 5 000 as it
allows milliseconds
[Music]
now we will add another custom module to
perform the click operation on the first
search results screen
[Music]
rename the step as per the activity
then add the click operation to the link
control
this operation will click on this link
from google search result
here we need to add the final
verification step to validate the
trisentis official portal
we will now drag another custom module
into this test case
this module will be used to verify the
logo of official try sentence portal
rename this step to verify tosca
official portal
[Music]
here we need to select the action mode
as verify to perform the verification
operation
[Music]
the verification will be done based on
the exist property value as true
the all the steps are created
now we need to close the browser
to perform close operation we will use
the standard module close browser
[Music]
the title of close browser standard
modules refer the title of the web
browser to be closed
we will use the string as trisentis
tosca asterisk as the title of the test
browser
here asterisk denotes any string after
the keyword trisentis tosca
the test case is ready now
by default tosca works with the internet
explorer
but we are working with chrome browser
here
so we will add one test configuration
parameter as browser
the value for this parameter should be
selected as chrome
[Music]
the test case is now completely
developed and ready to execute
we will understand the process for test
execution in next video
also we will discuss on usage of
libraries and parameterization in
upcoming videos
thanks for watching this video
that's all about tosca test case
creation
we will learn more about tosca data
parameterization in next tosca tutorial
please visit our website lambdageeks.com
for more articles on technology
engineering mathematics and various
other domain
you can check our other website as well
[Music]
we have features like youtube trends
twitter trends
scientific calculator and many more
other tools
[Music]
if you like our video please like
comment and share
if you have any questions please comment
and we will resolve your query